<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plot on inSileco</title>
    <link>https://insileco.github.io/tags/plot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plot on inSileco</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2021 inSileco</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insileco.github.io/tags/plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Curated list of R resources available online</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/wiki/usefulr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/wiki/usefulr/</guid>
      <description>Main sources of resources Comprehensive R Archive Network: CRAN  Manuals Contributed manuals and cheat sheets  Journals  R journal Journal of Statistical Software JOSS  Books  Bookdown  RStudio  Website: https://www.rstudio.com Books Cheat Sheet R Views  ROpensci  Website: https://ropensci.org/about/ ROpensci&amp;rsquo;s blog ROpensci&amp;rsquo;s packages Learn R  Tutorials  DataCamp  Tools  METACRAN A curation of R packages rdrr rdocumentation cloudyr  Blogs If you want to find people online writing about R, you should definitively check out R-bloggers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animations in R: Time series of erythemal irradiance in the St. Lawrence</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2017/07/05/animations-in-r-time-series-of-erythemal-irradiance-in-the-st.-lawrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2017/07/05/animations-in-r-time-series-of-erythemal-irradiance-in-the-st.-lawrence/</guid>
      <description>The “need” for animations 
As part of my PhD thesis, I am currently characterizing the intensity of multiple stressors in the estuary and gulf of St. Lawrence (see ResearchGate project for more details). I have recently needed (read: thought it would be cool) to create an animation of the temporal variations in ultra-violet intensity in the St. Lawrence. Here is how I did it.

 Setting up R R version used to build the last update of this post sessionInfo()[[1]]$version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add icons on your R plot</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2017/05/23/add-icons-on-your-r-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2017/05/23/add-icons-on-your-r-plot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Icons are very popular on websites to improve the visual grepping (i.e. visual optimization of eyeball search). We all know how to go at the top or the bottom of a website clicking on chevrons ( ). We are also familiar with simple symbols that allow us to click and edit the text we are typing (  ). Moreover, some web applications are so widespread than their logo appears in thousands of websites (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your R plot Hylian</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2017/04/14/make-your-r-plot-hylian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2017/04/14/make-your-r-plot-hylian/</guid>
      <description>Below are presented the 6 steps you need to make your plot a Hylian one! May the triforce be with you! 0. R Version sessionInfo()[[1L]]$version.string #R&amp;gt; [1] &amp;#34;R version 3.5.2 (2018-12-20)&amp;#34; 1. Open R and download the font The Triforce font is available on line. Below we download it using R. Alternatively, you may simply download and install it using a couple of clicks, if you proceed so, skip step 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of R packages to create and edit plots</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/wiki/rgraphpkgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/wiki/rgraphpkgs/</guid>
      <description>Note that the list of packages below would be updated as soon as we find a new package. If you know a package that should be in the list, please feel mention it in the disqus section below.

Why use R to produce graphics? S, R’s ancestor, was first designed to be an interactive interface for calling routines from the SCS (Statistical Computing Subroutines) FORTRAN library. It expanded to be a complete programming language dedicated to data manipulation, statistical analysis and data visualization (see A brief History of S).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>