<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on inSileco</title>
    <link>https://insileco.github.io/resource/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on inSileco</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2017-2023 inSileco</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://insileco.github.io/resource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our Software</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/resource/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/resource/software/</guid>
      <description>diskers [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Collection of seed dispersal kernels written in Rcpp. geographr [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; An R package to test your skills in world geography. graphicsutils [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Collection of graphics functions. inSilecoMisc [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Miscelleneous R functions. orthomap [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bug fix for map using orthographic projection. rchelsa [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; An R package to download chelsa data. rcites [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Access information from the Speciesplus database rcrosswords [R package] &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; An R package to generate crossword grids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our tutorials</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/resource/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/resource/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Short R tutorials About R Markdown (2018) Learn how to use R Markdown.
About R packages (2018) A short tutorial to learn how to created an R package.
Maps with R (2018) Learn how to turn R into a powerful GIS software.
Long-form R tutorials Utiliser R Markdown (2022) A long-form guide to master R Markdown.
R in Space (2018) A long-form guide to use R as a GIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curated list of R resources available online</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/resource/usefulr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/resource/usefulr/</guid>
      <description>Main sources of resources Comprehensive R Archive Network: CRAN Manuals Contributed manuals and cheat sheets Journals R journal Journal of Statistical Software JOSS Books Bookdown RStudio Website: https://www.rstudio.com Books Cheat Sheet R Views ROpensci Website: https://ropensci.org/about/ ROpensci&amp;rsquo;s blog ROpensci&amp;rsquo;s packages Learn R Tutorials Software carpenteries DataCamp Guru 99 Tools METACRAN A curation of R packages rdrr rdocumentation cloudyr Blogs If you want to find people online writing about R, you should definitively check out R-bloggers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful web links</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/resource/usefulurl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/resource/usefulurl/</guid>
      <description>The Internet&amp;hellip; so many websites, so many resources, how easy it is to get lost when navigating the vast digital ocean! Teaching how to identify credible online material is doubtlessly one of the biggest educational challenge of our time. As researchers with strong interests in computational methods in ecology, we spend a substantial amount of our time searching various kind of information online ranging from a small piece of code to massive ecological database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of R packages to create and edit plots</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/resource/rgraphpkgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/resource/rgraphpkgs/</guid>
      <description>Note that the list of packages below would be updated as soon as we find a new package. If you know a package that should be in the list, please feel mention it in the disqus section below.
Why use R to produce graphics? S, R&amp;rsquo;s ancestor, was first designed to be an interactive interface for calling routines from the SCS (Statistical Computing Subroutines) FORTRAN library. It expanded to be a complete programming language dedicated to data manipulation, statistical analysis and data visualization (see A brief History of S).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
