<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup on inSileco</title>
    <link>https://insileco.github.io/tags/setup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Setup on inSileco</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2021 inSileco</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insileco.github.io/tags/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My MacOS Setup</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2018/07/13/my-macos-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2018/07/13/my-macos-setup/</guid>
      <description>My MacOS Setup Inspired by Kevin&amp;rsquo;s recent post on setting up his new laptop on Debian Stretch, I decided that it was time to reset my Mac BookPro to factory settings. I bought it after a year in my thesis and I&amp;rsquo;ve grown quite a bit since then in my understanding of programming and computers in general. That also meant that I had a lot of accumulated junk!
I also figured that I should do so using a bash script so that I could make this whole process as reproducible as possible for the next time or if I have to change my laptop for some obscure reason!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My R setup on Debian</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2018/06/18/my-r-setup-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2018/06/18/my-r-setup-on-debian/</guid>
      <description>R 3.5.0 &amp;ldquo;Joy in playing&amp;rdquo; was released April 23rd this year. It took a couple of weeks before it was made available on Debian testing due to the work required to rebuild the packages and as a Debian user that spend a lot of time on R, I am extremely grateful to the work of Dirk, Michael and Johannes on this!
I thought it was a good opportunity to write few notes about my R setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Debian Testing!</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2018/05/21/go-debian-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2018/05/21/go-debian-testing/</guid>
      <description>For almost a year now I&amp;rsquo;ve being spending most of my computer time on Debian. I began with Debian Stretch and switched to Debian Testing two months ago. This was another good opportunity to gain skills and I&amp;rsquo;d like to report about my transition in this post.
What really happened? The hope of a seamless transition Last Easter, after a couple of months on Debian Stretch, I felt like the time had come for me to go Debian Testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting my Debian Stretch up</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/2018/01/21/setting-my-debian-stretch-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/2018/01/21/setting-my-debian-stretch-up/</guid>
      <description>This post details my Debian Stretch setup on my Lenovo ThinkPad T470p. I got this machine in early August 2017, so I now have almost 6 months worth of experience on Debian and I thought it was a good time to 1- document the rationale behind my move from MacOS to Debian 2- explain how I set my computer up and 3- how I rate my appreciation of working on Debian.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>