<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R in Space on inSileco</title>
    <link>https://insileco.github.io/tags/r-in-space/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R in Space on inSileco</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2021 inSileco</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://insileco.github.io/tags/r-in-space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - A Series</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_homepage/</guid>
      <description>So it begins A fair proportion of people involved in inSileco have one particular expertise in common: we work extensively with spatial data. This expertise has been developed through extensive time importing, creating and formatting spatial data, performing spatial analyses and building static and dynamic spatial visualizations.
In this blog post series, we propose an educational tour of spatial possibilities offered by tools developed in the R environment. This series could thus be used in an educational setting to learn how to use R in Space!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - Useful resources</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_refs/</guid>
      <description>The mapping landscape has changed! Over the last decade it has become increasingly easy to create and edit maps. As explained by Mark Zastrow in “Science on the Map&amp;rdquo;, the mapping landscape has dramatically changed over the last decade. Scientists can now readily draw valuable spatial representations of their work, even with large data sets and perform powerful analyses using specific packages of programming languages such as R and Python. In order to give you a taste of the diversity of tool to manipulate, analyze and visualize geographic information, we listed a few software available:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - About spatial data</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_spobjects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_spobjects/</guid>
      <description>Spatial data refer to phenomenon or information that can be observed geographically. What a definition! In short spatial data concern every information that could be reported on a map, i.e. on a two-dimensions geographical coordinates system. Two kinds of spatial data exist: vector data and raster data. Generally vectors refer to discrete locations, i.e. objects with boundaries (for instance a city, a road, a country) whereas raster data refer to continuous phenomenon that can be observed everywhere, but without natural boundaries (for instance the surface temperature).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - Import spatial objects</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_import/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_import/</guid>
      <description>Reading and writing spatial objects with sf and raster Spatial data are encoded in various GIS file formats such as Shapefiles (.shp), Geodatabase (.gdb), GeoPackage (.gpkg) and GeoJSON (.geojson), GeoTIFF (.tiff). In this post we show how to read commonly used formats and import the data they include in you R session. We start by describing the steps to turn a set of coordinates included in a .csv file into a spatial object and write it to a GIS file format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - Basic mapping</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_basicmapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_basicmapping/</guid>
      <description>Plot methods for sp objects Let’s first get some data:
library(sp) library(sf) library(raster) dir.create(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;) bel1 &amp;lt;- getData(&amp;quot;GADM&amp;quot;, country = &amp;quot;BEL&amp;quot;, level = 1, path = &amp;quot;data/&amp;quot;) bel2 &amp;lt;- getData(&amp;quot;GADM&amp;quot;, country = &amp;quot;BEL&amp;quot;, level = 2, path = &amp;quot;data/&amp;quot;) Quick plot:
plot(bel1) Two quick plots:
par(mfrow = c(1,2), mar = c(0,0,0,0)) plot(bel1, col = 1:3) plot(bel2, lty = 2) Slightly customized plots:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - Attribute manipulations</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_attrmanip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_attrmanip/</guid>
      <description>Spatial objects attributes manipulations Now that we know how to import and transform different classes of spatial objects in R, we can start manipulating their attributes. In this post, we will make a brief overview of some useful basic manipulations that we can perform on spatial object attributes. By no means are those examples exhaustive, but they constitute common manipulations that are made with spatial objects.

Vector objects For this part, we discuss how to manipulate attributes of objects from the sf package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - Geometry manipulation</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_geomanip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_geomanip/</guid>
      <description>To manipulate geometries, there are few options. For spatial objects defined with sp, there is a specific package to manipulate vector objects: rgeos. The equivalent of most common functions in sp are found in sf. Finally, there are a set of interesting functions in raster to handle the manipulation of rasters with vector objects.
Let’s first load the packages required and download a simple shapefile of Belgium.
library(sp) library(sf) library(rgeos) library(raster) dir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - R spatial data resources</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_rdataresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_rdataresources/</guid>
      <description>R data resources With the R community as vibrant and dynamic as it is, there are an increasingly high number of online data resources readily available to users through simple lines of command. The best hub of R packages making online data available to R users is actively developed by the rOpenSci group. This non-profit organization aims at foster[ing] a culture that values open and reproducible research using shared data and reusable software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R in Space - Custom mapping</title>
      <link>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_custommaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://insileco.github.io/tuto/rinspace/rinspace_custommaps/</guid>
      <description>Creating a thematic map In this post, we go through all the steps required to produce a complete good-looking map. We will see how to add a title, a legend, a scale, axis and a North arrow and choose a good color palette. To do so, we will use the Quebec province as our sampled area.
So, first, we import 2 vector layers readily available in R, the Canadian provincial boundaries and USA country boundary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>